# Dr. Jonathan Belcher

4650 White Rock Cir Apt 6
Boulder, CO 80301

✓ jonathan.belcher@colorado.edu

✓ belchr.github.io/

✓ github.com/Belchr

Ph.D. Mathematics, CU Boulder

## Professional Interests and Goals

I AM a passionate mathematician and educator with a background in non-commutative geometry, topology, functional analysis, and differential geometry. I also have interests and side projects in data science, crypto currencies, finance, and investing. My goal is to apply my broad mathematical knowledge and teaching experience towards developing curricula in engineering and applied sciences. I also enjoy mentoring and motivating developing minds, helping to guide them towards career fields that will interest and inspire them. The current challenges our civilization faces are going to require a strong, disciplined, and insightful generation of people. With the setbacks of COVID-19 and diminishing efficacy of our K-12 educational programs, it is up to the innovation of our post-secondary institutions to make sure that the next generation has the preparation they need for our rapidly changing world. This is a challenge that excites and inspires me, and I love to work with institutions that feel similarly with the sentiment that education is one of the most powerful tools we have to change the world.

# History

2022—Present **Post-Doctoral Teacher/Researcher**, Convex Optimization and Machine Learning, University of Colorado, Boulder

2019 – 2022 Mathematics Lecturer, University of Colorado, Boulder

2012 – 2019 Graduate Student in Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

2009 - 2012 Education Editor, McGraw-Hill Education and Independent Contractor

2009 – 2009 Actuarial Contractor, Nationwide Insurance

### Education

May, 2019 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

May, 2016 M.A. Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

June, 2009 B.S. Mathematics, The Ohio State University

June, 2009 B.S. Physics, The Ohio State University

#### Mentoring

 ${\it Thesis} \quad {\bf A} \ {\bf Generalization} \ {\bf of} \ {\bf S-Divergence} \ {\bf to} \ {\bf Symmetric} \ {\bf Cone} \ {\bf Programming} \ {\bf via} \ {\bf Euclidean} \ {\bf Jorc} \ {\it Co-advising} \quad {\bf dan} \ {\bf Algebra}, \ {\it Zhuochen} \ ({\it Jaden}) \ {\it Wang}$ 

Math / Logan Martin - Geometric Unity, Mathematical Physics, Aerospace Engineering

Curriculum Kevin Stull - Natural Language Processing, Neurolink, Data Science, Machine Learning

Advising Dominic Glimp - Algebraic Topology, Differential Geometry, Analysis

# Technical Skills

- Python, NumPy, SymPy, Jupyter Notebooks
- Data Analysis, Data Visualization with Pandas/python
- SQL scripting, Excel, and VBA, Nationwide Insurance
- C++ and Matlab intro courses, The Ohio State University
- Canvas Building course pages, organizing gradebook, using design tools, kaltura videos, integrating gradescope, webassign, google docs, and third party apps.
- Zoom Scheduling and running courses, uploading recordings to youtube and canvas, using proctorio
- YouTube Online Lecture Series, Teaching and Leadership

Teaching Summary

Lecturer MATH 2510: Intro to Statistics 5 Semesters APPM 2360: Differential Equations with Linear Algebra 2 Semester MATH 2130: Linear Algebra 1 Semester APPM 2350: Calculus III for Engineers 2 Semesters MATH 2400: Calculus III 2 Semesters APPM 1360: Calculus II for Engineers 2 Semester MATH 2300: Calculus II 3 Semesters APPM 1350: Calculus I for Engineers 2 Semester MATH 1300: Calculus I 3 Semester MATH 1150: Precalculus 4 Semesters MATH 1212: Data and Models 3 Semesters MATH 1081: Business Calculus 1 Semester Work Groups APPM 1390: A Game for Calc 3 1 Semester APPM —: Mathematical Brain Training 1 Semester Teaching MATH 1300: Calculus I 1 Semester Assistant MATH 1150: Precalculus 2 Semesters MATH 1011: College Algebra 1 Semester

Diversity and Young Scholars Summer Bridge Program, The Ohio State University, Summer 2008 Inclusion

Ph.D. Thesis

Supervisor Markus Pflaum

## Publications

In preparation Bridge Cohomology: A generalization of Hochschild and cyclic cohomologies with applications to manifolds with boundary, Jon Belcher and Markus Pflaum

#### Awards and Honors

 $\it Talk$  Bridge Cohomology: Generalizing Hochschild and Cyclic Cohomologies via Triangulated Categories

Invited Online Global Noncommutative Geometry Seminar. Org: Xiang Tang, Guoliang Yu. Aug. 12, 2020
Invited AMS Special Session on Quantum Theory of Matter Meets Noncommutative Geometry and Topology,
I. January 2020

Talk Bridge Cohomology: Generalizing Hochschild and Cyclic Cohomologies.

CIMPA School for Noncommutative Geometry. Meridas, Mexico. December 2018

AMS Fall Western Sectional. October 2018

K-Theory Conference, Argentina. July 2018

Texas A&M Noncommutative Geometry Conference. May 2018

Fellowships Summer 2018 Adele V. Leonhardy Memorial Scholarship, \$4K

Summer 2017 University of Colorado Graduate School Summer Fellowship \$4.5K

Summer 2016 Sieglinde Haller Scholarship, \$4.5K

Certification Society of Actuaries Exam P

2008

#### Service

Math The Geometry of Classical and Quantum Fields, Liber Mathematicae, Markus Pflaum, Jon Community Belcher (Contributing Author), www.libermath.org/GeometryClassicalAndQuantumFields/Contributions Fall 2017

Gone Fishing: Conference on Poisson Geometry, Assistant Organizer, March 10-13, 2016 The Serre-Swan Theorem, expository paper contributed to The CRing Project, Akhil Mathew, M. Pflaum, et al., Spring 2016

Volunteering Boulder Committee on Rights and Compensation - Board Member, Database 2018-2019 and Membership Records Manager

Andy 24 Memorial Charity Event

2008 - 2010

# Work Experience

- 2009-2012 Education Editor, McGraw-Hill Education and Independent Contractor
  - Edited online mathematical content using web applications
- 2009 2009 Actuarial Contractor, Nationwide Insurance
  - Built and tested code factors for new life insurance products
  - $\bullet~$  Fixed and reported on product defects through logical analysis of system code and databases with SQL and VBA